## Aldo Valencia

#### **Profile**

Dedicated United States Marine Staff Non-Commissioned Officer with 14 years of career experience in managing, organizing, leading and mentoring Marines under my supervision. Achieved the grade of E-7/GySgt in my years of active duty service.

Experienced in training over 100 Marines to fulfill mission requirements essential to the command.

Expanded my duties by serving as the Equal Opportunity Representative for over two years implementing quality controls for a safer environment.

Driven and enthusiastic, with the ability to manage projects and people.

### **Employment History**

Operations Management Division Staff Non Commissioned Officer in Charge , USMC , MCAS Beaufort, SC

APRIL 2021 - PRESENT

- Responsible for leading, mentoring, supervising, and developing (25) subordinate Marines and performing other tasks as directed.
- Directly supervised the support of 4 flying squadrons with 49 aircraft within MAG-31 and MALS-31 IMA work centers ensuring appropriate and timely support and readiness.

# Marine Aircraft Group 31 Squadron Gunnery Sergeant, USMC, MCAS Beaufort, SC

NOVEMBER 2019 - MARCH 2021

- Responsible for over 40 administrative packages for 20 meritorious promotions, NCOQ, and MOQ boards resulting in 34 meritorious promotions and 6 NCO/MOQ winners.
- Managed all personnel tasks from 2d Marine Aircraft Wing to provide direct support for missions, training exercises, and individual augment deployment for CENTCOM.
- -Planned and facilitated the Lance Corporal Leadership and Ethics Seminars for 225 Lance Corporals and Private First Classes to support 8 commands in total.

#### Operations Chief, USMC, MCAS Camp Pendleton, CA

MARCH 2018 - OCTOBER 2019

- Instrumental in the implementation of a Lance Corporal Seminar course which led to (42) Marines graduating and completing the seminar.
- Successfully assisted the Operations Officer in the planning, sourcing, and ongoing Operational Aviation Logistical support to over (200) Marines across (5) deployments.
- Effectively coordinated, planned and supervised approximately (700) Marines in all training requirements achieving above 80% training mission goals.

Future Operations Chief, USMC, MCRD San Diego, CA

APRIL 2017 - FEBRUARY 2018

#### **Details**

808-782-9627 valenciaaldo0303@gmail.com

#### **Skills**

**Customer Service** 

**Excellent Communication Skills** 

Integrity

Leadership Skills

Teamwork Skills

Management

#### Languages

**English** 

Spanish

- Coordinated, planned, and supervised the itineraries of special guests and groups visiting Recruit Training Regiment training areas and facilities to include: the Commandant of the Marine Corps General Neller.
- Maintain awareness, track requirements, and deconflict friction points to facilitate the execution of all major events whether sponsored or supported by the regiment.
- Responsible for assisting the Future Operations/Special Projects Officer in the initial planning of support requirements, the production of letters of instruction and fragmentary orders, and dissemination of finalized information in order to facilitate and ensure subordinate unit comprehension and compliance for major events or visits.

#### **Education**

Equal Opportunity Representative, MCAS Beaufort, SC

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

Senior Enlisted Joint Professional Education, MCAS Camp Pendleton, CA

MARCH 2019 - APRIL 2019

SNCO Career Course School, MCRD San Diego, CA

MAY 2017 - APRIL 2018

High School Diploma, Smoky Hill High School, Colorado

SEPTEMBER 2006 - MAY 2008

#### References

Maj Psyhogis from USMC

770-876-3125

MGySgt Pullins from USMC

252-259-4388

1stLt Trenum from USMC

703-615-7911

1stLt Cartwright from USMC

928-446-8210

1stLt Tilstra from USMC

920-539-7990